어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!
겨우 살아 돌아온 무사시는 한가이 있는 것도 잠시, 시라누이 일족이 지라이얀을 쫒으며 나타났다.
Not long after reviving and taking some leisurely time, Shiranui Clan appeared, chasing Jiraiyan.
그렇지만 모두의 힘으로 이걸 물리쳤다.
But with everyone's power, they repelled them.
다만 지라이얀이 남긴 말, 히미코가 시라누이 일족의 여왕이라고 한 것은 무사시의 마음을 박살냈다.
But the words Jiraiyan left before he left, that Himiko is the queen of Shiranui Clan, has knocked down Musashi's heart.
여기저기
화재이오
Fire
Here and There
무사시! 어디 있어!
Musashi! Where are you?
여기도 없으니 원!
He's not here? Really!
무사시! 그런 곳에 있었구나! 언제까지 있을 거야! 어서 나와!
Musashi! You were there! When will you be done? Get out promptly!
잠깐, 나이오!
Wait, it's me-gowasu!
죄송합니다!
I'm sorry!
어라, 코지로!
Hey, Kojirō!
미안해! 화장하고 있었구나!
Excuse me! I see you're putting on makeup!
아니에요! 왜 제가 살금살금 숨어서 화장해야 하는 건데요?! 정말...
No way! Why would I want to hide and put on my makeup?! Really...
그러니까, 정말 안 했어?
Well... are you sure that you didn't?
당연하죠!
Of course!
아, 근데, 무사시한테 급한 일이라도?
Oh, anyway, do you need to see Musashi right now?
아무리 찾아도 없어. 어디 갔는지.
I've been finding him everywhere, but I couldn't find him. I wonder where is him...
그렇습니까. 분명 지라이얀과 싸우고 헤어진 건 그들답지 않다고 생각했습니다.
I see. I did think that fighting and splitting up with Jiraiyan isn't like them.
그렇지?
You know it!!
뭐, 주제넘게 나서서 바보를 상대하느니 조금은 멍하니 있게 두는 쪽이 덜 귀찮으니 낫죠.
Well, I guess leaving him be like that is better than being impertinent and bothering oneself to interact with a fool.
나, 생각하고 있었는데, 지라이얀이 말한 그 히미코 말야.
Do you know what? About Himiko lady Jiraiyan told me about...
서, 설마, 무슨!
N- no way! That's impossible!
그 히미코야말로 시라누이 일족의 여왕이야! 조심해, 무사시!
That Himiko is the queen of Shiranui Clan! Be careful, Musashi!
거짓말이오! 엉터리이오!
That's a lie-dasu! That's nonsense-dasu!
그래도 지라이얀이 나한테 거짓말을 할 리도 없고...
But Jiraiyan wouldn't lie to me...
그 사람이 시라누이의 여왕?
That person is Shiranui's queen?
뭘 풀이 죽어 있냐!
Why are you dejected?
갑자기 큰 목소리 내니 심장이 멈추었소!
Your sudden loud voice has stopped my heartbeat-dasu!
그러니까, 아무리 불러도 답이 없었잖아.
You didn't respond when we called you!
자, 뭐 생각해?
Hey, tell me what you're thinking!
아, 아니, 딱히...
N- no, not really...
무사시. 네 목표는 뭐냐.
Musashi. What do you want to achieve?
그건 당연히 지팡구 제일의
That's, of course, to become the number one-
아니, 어리니까 사랑을 하는 것도 좋지.
But you're young now. It's not a bad thing to love someone.
다만.
But.
네게는 오츠루라는 애인이 있잖아! 꽤 오랫동안 안 나왔으니까 잊어버린 사람도 있겠지만.
You have a lover named Otsuru! Maybe some people have forgotten about her as it's been a while since she showed up.
무사시 씨! 어서 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되세요! 오츠루 부탁해요!
Mr. Musashi! Hurry up and become the number one martial artist of Jipangu! Otsuru is asking you!
그치? 오츠루 씨를 슬프게 할 짓을 하면 안 돼. 일거양득하려다가 일거양실한다는 말도 있잖아.
Right? You must not do anything that will make Ms. Otsuru sad. He who runs after two hares will catch neither, they say.
그래, 무사시!
He's right, Musashi!
둘 다 뭔 소리이오! 내, 내게는 하나도 모르겠소!
What are you two talking about-dasu? I- I don't get it at all-dasu!
너 히미코라는 사람하고 사귀고 있지? 자백해!
Aren't you making friends with someone named Himiko? Spit it out!
저런저런, 둘 다 오해이오! 무엇보다도 히미코 씨는 내 엄마하고 같은 나이이오!
No, no, you two are misunderstanding-dasu! Most of all, Ms. Himiko is as old as my mother-dasu!
사랑하면 나이차는 아무것도 아니라는 말도 있지.
They also say that with love, age difference isn't a problem.
나, 오츠루 씨에게 편지 쓸까?
Should I write a letter to Ms. Otsuru?
아니, 그건...
No, you can't!
그럼 솔직히 말해! 상담해 줄 테니까!
Then spit it out! I'll give you a consultation!
어디까지 진행한 거야? 말해 봐!
How far did you go? Tell me!
그건...
That's...
어! 좋은 남자!
Look! A good man!
어, 어디? 어디, 어디, 어디?
Hey, where? Where, where, where?
이제 됐소!
Forget it-dasu!
아, 멈춰!
Hey, stop!
으아, 센히메 님!
Senhime!
두꺼비 기름 상인이 우리 우는 아기도 뚝 그치게 한다는 사쿠라지마 일당에 뭔 일이냐!
What does a Toad Oil seller have to do with Sakurajima Gang that's told to make a crying baby stop?!
이 자식! 뭐가 이상하냐!
You bastard! What's so funny?!
싸우러 왔으면 그냥은 안 보내준다!
If you're here to fight us, we won't let you go so easily!
묻고 싶은 게 있다.
I have something to ask you.
네...
Yessir...
시라누이 일족의 아지트는 어디냐?
Where is the base of Shiranui Clan?
모릅니다.
I don't know.
몰라.
No idea.
제길. 얘들도 틀렸나.
Damn. They're also useless.
개굴개굴! 개굴개굴! 개굴개굴!
ribbit-ribbit! ribbit-ribbit! ribbit-ribbit!
무사시가 저 만큼이나 히미코를 믿고 있으면, 얘한테 아무리 말해보았자 생각을 바꿀 리가 없지.
If Musashi's believing in Himiko that much, there's no way he's going to change his mind just by talking to him.
역시. 이 내가 어떻게든 히미코가 어디 있는지 찾아내야 해.
Of course. I have to find out where Himiko is by myself.
히미코 씨에게 구해진 건 분명 이 주변!
I was rescued by Ms. Himiko around this place!
뭘 해서라도 그 사람을 찾아내서 직접 물어볼 수밖에 없소!
I must do anything to find out that person and ask her personally-dasu!
무사시 님이 어딜 갔는지도 말 안 했소?
Did Mr. Musashi not tell you where's he going-gowasu?
응, 그래. 내가 걱정하고 있었는데.
Yes, I was so worried about him.
대체 뭘 생각하고 있던 거야? 자식이 부모 마음 모른다더니!
What were he thinking?! It's just like the saying no child knows how dear he is to his parents!
봤냐?
Did you see?
아니오.
No.
분명 이 주변이오. 저곳에서 떨어졌으니...
The place is here-dasu. I fell from that place...
틀림없소. 여기서 나 정신을 잃어서...
No doubt about it-dasu. I lost consciousness around here...
母ちゃん！
夢か。。。
ムサシさん、気が付きまして。
히미코 씨 집에서 간병받았소!
I was nursed at Ms. Himiko's house-dasu!
はい、あ！・あー！
히미코 씨!
Ms. Himiko!
すまんだす。トイレはどこだすか。
はいはい、私がお連れしますよ。
本当に、こうしてると、おいら、母ちゃんといる見たんだす。
私はそんなにムサシさんのお母様に似ているのかしら。
いや、おいら、母ちゃんにあったことないダス。
気が付いたら、独りぼっちだったダスから。。。
히미코 씨!
Ms. Himiko!
이건...
This...
음. 그렇구나.
Oh. I see.
사쿠라지마
Sakurajima
수고했다.
Good job.
히미코 씨!
Ms. Himiko!
어이!
Hey!
아무도 없고, 들어갈 수 있을 것 같지도 않소.
Nobody's there, and I don't think anybody can get in-dasu.
누구이오!
Who's there-dasu?!
시라누이 일족인 것이오! 나오시오! 본명히 하고 싶은 것이 있소!
You are Shiranui Clan-dasu! Come out! I want to make something clear-dasu!
급속히 수가 늘다니 치사하오!
Increasing your number so quickly is cheating-dasu!
비겁하오!
How cowardly-dasu!
너희 보스의 이름은 뭣이오!
What's the name of your boss-dasu?!
훈련의 성과를 보여주어라!
Show him the result of our training!
알겠습니다!
Got it!
으악! 뭣이오, 이건!
Wah! What the heck is this-dasu?!
흥! 여기까지는 못 올 것이오! 어서 보스의 이름을 대시오!
Hmph! You can't get up to here-dasu! Now spit out the name of your boss-dasu!
나무 키 줄이기!
Tree height reduction!
뭣이오, 뭣이오?
What's this-dasu? What's this-dasu?
이래도 말 안 할 것이오?!
Are you still shutting your mouths-dasu?!
이번엔 이쪽에서 가오!
It's my turn now-dasu!
퇴각!
Retreat!
멈추시오!
Stop-dasu!
젠장! 달아나는 건 빠른 놈들이오!
Damn! They sure run away quickly-dasu!
겉만 번지르르하오.
They're all mere show-dasu!
기분 탓이오?
Was it just me-dasu?
역시 기분 탓이오.
It's probably me-dasu.
돌아왔소!
I'm back-dasu!
시라누이 일족은 대체 뭘 꾸미고 있는가?
What is Shiranui Clan planning?
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
막 돌아왔소!
I'm back now-dasu!
와, 오늘은 좋은 날씨여서 이런 시간까지 산책하고 말았소...
Today's weather was so good, and I couldn't help but to take a walk until now-dasu...
문명개화
(bunmei kaika: lit. civilization; basically westernization; govt. system revamp in Meiji Period)
bunmei kaika
센짱, 돌아왔소...
Sen-chan, I'm back-dasu...
아깐 미안했소. 나 오늘은 날씨가 좋아서 산책했소!
I'm sorry for that-dasu. I was strolling since the weather was so good today-dasu!
어라? 모두는?
Huh? Where's everybody?
지금 주베가 와서 이야기하고 있어.
Jūbē came and they're discussing.
그렇소...
That's it-dasu...
정말 잘못한 줄은 알고 있어? 사람 걱정하게 만들고.
Do you know you were bad today? You left us worried!
물론이오!
Of course-dasu!
그럼 이번만은 용서해 줄게!
Then I'll forgive you this time!
어땠는지 말해 줘!
Tell me how was it!
뭐, 뭐가오?
A- about what-dasu?
어물쩍 넘기려 하지 말고! 히미코 씨하고 데이트.
Don't try to dodge! About the date with Ms. Himiko!
아, 아, 아니오!
N- no, no, that's not it-dasu!
그래? 나도 오츠루한테 편지 썼어.
Oh, is that so? I wrote a letter to Otsuru.
전략. 오츠루, 무사시는 바람 피우고 있습니다..
Omitting the preface, Musashi is cheating on you.
무사시 씨! 잠깐 한눈판 사이에!
Mr. Musashi! How can you do that while I was taking my off you!
이제 절교에요! 저리 치우세요!
I'm breaking up with you! Get your filthy face off me!
자, 편지 부치러 가야지.
Now I'm going to mail this letter.
아, 잠깐!
Hey, wait!
그러니까 이건 연애 경험 가득한 내가 상담해 줄 테니까!
Then, I'll give you a consultation, since I have a lot of experiences with love!
센짱 맨날 짝사랑이잖소.
Your loves are all unrequited-dasu.
거긴 안 되오!
Not there-dasu!
무사시, 왔냐!
Musashi, are you back?
코지로! 살려주시오.
Kojirō! Help me!
무사시, 센히메 님, 사이고 님이 부르십니다.
Musashi, Senhime, Mr. Saigo is calling you people.
코지로는 비겁자!
Kojirō, you're a coward!
아, 힘들다. 오늘도 하루종일 헛걸음질했네.
I'm tired. No gain today after all this walking again...
대체 어디에 시라누이 일족이 숨어 있는 거야?
Where is that Shiranui Clan hiding in?
케로키치, 너 어디 갔었어?
Kerokichi, where did you go?
뭐?! 옆이?!
What?! Neighbor?!
저건!
Those people!
정말, 이 가면을 쓰면 얼굴이 쪄서 말야!
I hate that this mask makes my face hot!
그래, 그래!
Yeah, yeah!
몰랐다... 분명 이 주변에 살고 있는 건 맞는데, 설마 옆에 있었을 줄이야...
I didn't know... I knew they were living somewhere around, but not the next to me!
그럼 시라누이 일족의 본거지는 사쿠라지마에 있다는 것이오?
So, are you saying that the base of Shiranui Clan is at Sakurajima-gowasu?
부하가 상세히 모은 정보를 분석, 검토한 결과로 이번에야말로 틀림없이.
After analyzing and examining the data gathered by my men, there's no doubt about it this time.
꽤나 자신있어 보이오.
You look pretty confident-dasu.
그렇습니다. 여러분, 규슈에 오래 전부터 전해져 오는 전설을 알고 계신가요?
That's right. Everyone, have you heard of the old legend of Kyushu?
그렇소. 오래 전에 이 땅에는 불의 나라의 여왕이 지배하는 고대 국가가 있었다고 하는 것 말인가.
Yes, if you're saying about the ancient country named the Fire Country, ruled by a queen, on this land-gowasu.
불의 나라? 고대 국가?
Fire Country? Ancient country?
나라는 번영해, 사람들은 일하는 것을 잊어 사치스러운 생활을 했다고 전해지오.
The country has prospered, and people forgot how to work and lived extravagantly-gowasu.
그건 대단하오.
That's awesome-dasu.
그러나 어느 날...
But one day...
수호신의 진화가 일어나 순식간에 불의 나라를 멸망시키고 말았다고 전해지오.
Their guardian deity has erupted, and ended up perishing that Fire Country-gowasu.
그럼 사람들도 전부...
Then, all the people must've been...
아니, 극히 일부지만 달아나서 살아남은 자가 있다고 들었소.
No. It's an extremely small group of people, but some are told to be alive-gowasu.
즉 시라누이 일족이야말로 그 남은 자들의 후손이란 것입니다.
Meaning that Shiranui Clan is descendant of those survived people.
그 닌자들 말이오?
You mean, those ninjas-dasu?
그들이 바라는 것은 다시 불의 나라를 일으키는 것.
What they want is reviving that Fire Country.
그렇구나. 그래서 천하를 노리는 한조하고 손을 잡았는가.
I see. That's why they've teamed up with Hanzo, looking to rule over the country.
히미코 씨가 그 시라누이의 여왕... 그럴 리가...
Ms. Himiko is the queen of Shiranui... no way...
화재다!
Fire!
서둘러라!
Hurry!
정말이오!
True-dasu!
다들 피난해라! 서둘러!
Everyone, escape! Hurry!
저기에는 불의 기운이 없는 곳. 이상하오.
There's nothing combustible over there. That's not right-gowasu.
어쩌오, 코지로!
What should we do, Kojirō?!
일단 불을 꺼야 한다!
We have to put off the fire first!
으악, 큰일이오!
This is bad-dasu!
무사시! 비켜라!
Musashi! Move!
코지로.
Kojirō.
아, 미안...
I'm... sorry...
체스트!
Chest!
누구 짓이오!
Whose doing is this-gowasu?!
역시 시라누이 일족이었소!
I knew it was Shiranui Clan-gowasu!
내가 상대하오!
I'll face you-dasu!
센히메 님은 제가 지키겠소!
I'll protect Senhime-gowasu!
부탁드립니다!
Please do so!
코지로! 멋져! 미남! 호남!
Kojirō! Cool! Handsome! Good man!
흥.
Hmph.
체스트!
Chest!
밖에서 불을 피우는 동료가 있는가!
It seems that their comrade is setting fire from outside!
찾아내서 쓰러트리지 않는 한 끝이 없다!
Unless we find them out and take down, there's no end to this!
좋소! 내가 처리해 주겠소!
Alright! I'll take care of them-dasu!
모습을 안 보이고 공격하다니 비겁하오!
Attacking without showing yourself is cowardly-dasu!
어딜 보냐.
Where are you looking at?
갑자기 나오다니 치사하오!
Appearing out of nowhere is cheating-dasu!
시라누이 일족의 가엔마. 너희들을 처치하기 위해 등장!
Gaenma of Shiranui Clan is here to get rid of you people!
화승의 가엔마
Gaenma of Fuse
가엔마인지 도마인진 모르겠지만 내 이천일류를 받아 보시오!
I don't care that you're Gaenma or gamma-dasu, but you'll take my Nitenichiryu-dasu!
각오!
Prepare yourself!
무사시!
Musashi!
비검 츠바메가에시!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
사라졌소!
He disappeared-dasu!
화둔술인가.
Fire Camouflage, eh.
여기다, 여기다!
Here, here!
뭐라고 말하는 것이오, 가엔마!
What are you saying, Gaenma?!
가엔마, 거기서 기다리시오!
Gaenma, you just wait there-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
-무사시!
-위험하오! 요술이라면 내게 맡기시오.
-Musashi!
-It's dangerous-gowasu! Leave that guy to me-gowasu.
체스트!
Chest!
사이고 씨!
Mr. Saigo!
어떠냐. 내 요술에서 빠져나가는 것은 불가능하다!
How's that? You cannot escape from my magic!
사이고 씨!
Mr. Saigo!
가공할 놈이구려. 괜찮소이다.
He's dreadful. But I'm fine-gowasu.
시건방지긴! 모두 한꺼번에 저 세상에 보내주마!
How impudent! You're all going to hell!
눈이!
My eyes!
지금이오!
Now!
체스트!
Chest!
제기랄!
Damn!
각오!
Prepare yourself!
둘이 같이 베다니 너무해!
Cutting together is cruel!
오늘은 여기까지! 퇴각!
That's it for today! Retreat!
숨어 있었구나.
They were hiding!
주베 님!
Mr. Jūbē!
저런! 무너진다!
No! It's collapsing!
다들 떨어져라!
Everyone, get away!
그래도 아직 무사시가!
But Musashi's still there!
일단 빨리!
Anyway, just hurry!
무사시! 어디 있어! 무사시!
Musashi! Where are you?! Musashi!
무사시!
Musashi!
센히메 일행의 걱정을 뒤로 하고 시라누이 일족으로 변장해 달아나는 잔당에 잠입한 무사시.
Leaving Senhime and others' worry behind, Musashi disguised himself as Shiranui Clan and smuggled to the fleeing remnants.
그러나 이런 모습 꼴불견이다!
But! You're so unsightly!
질풍노도의 다음 이야기를 기다려라!
Wait for the stormy next story!
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't worry too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep going! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
시라누이로 변장해서 사쿠라지마에 들어간 나.
I entered Sakurajima, disguising as Shiranui.
역시 히미코 씨는 시라누이 일족의 여왕이었소.
That Ms. Himiko really is the queen of Shiranui-dasu.
지금까지 속고 있었다니, 나, 정말 바보이오!
I was being fooled all time-dasu! I am an idiot!
그러나 한조하고 싸우는 나를 구해준 건 히미코 씨였소!
But the one to rescue me fighting Hanzo was Ms. Himiko-dasu!
다음 이야기! 불의 나라의 여왕 히미코이오
Next story! The Queen of the Fire Country, Himiko
질풍노도의 사쿠라지마이오!
It's the stormy Sakurajima-dasu!
다음 이야기
불의 나라의 여왕
히미코이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
The Queen of the Fire Country
Himiko
Look forwards for it!